Chiho Choi, Ph.D. 1/6

Chiho Choi, Ph.D.

Senior Scientist, Honda Research Institute USA

CONTACT INFROMATION

Honda Research Institute USA Inc. Website 70 Rio Robles, San Jose, CA 95134 LinkedIn chihochoi@outlook.com Google Scholar

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests span the fields of computer vision, machine learning, and robotics, focusing on understanding and prediction of human behavior in multi-agent interacting environments. In this area, I build a new perspective for safe operation of autonomous systems designed to cooperate with humans.

Behavior Reasoning

- Motion Prediction
- Activity Forecasting
- Relational Inference

- Uncertainty Modeling
- Interactive Planning
- Human Pose Prediction
 Pose Estimation

WORK EXPERIENCE

Honda Research Institute (HRI) USA

San Jose, CA, USA July 2021 – Present

Senior Scientist

- Leading multiple projects on vision-based future prediction research at Honda Research Institute USA.
- Supervising researchers and interns as a group leader.

Scientist February 2018 – June 2021

· Worked on understanding, reasoning, and prediction of human states and behaviors in multi-agent interacting environments.

HERE Technologies

Chicago, IL, USA

Intern

May 2017 - August 2017

- Worked on traffic scene understanding (detection and recognition) for automated driving.
- Developed a solution to learn from imbalanced data for generic machine learning systems.
- Supervisor: Dr. Xiang Ma and Prof. Xin Chen

EDUCATION

Purdue University

West Lafayette, IN, USA

Ph.D., Electrical and Computer Engineering

May 2018

May 2013

- Specialization: deep learning, detection, tracking, 3D vision
- · Committee members: Karthik Ramani, Stanley H. Chan, Mireille Boutin, Jeffrey M. Siskind

University of Southern California

Los Angeles, CA, USA

M.S., Electrical Engineering

• Specialization: 3D shape matching, registration

• Advisor: Prof. Suya You, Department of Computer Science

Hanyang University

Seoul, Korea

B.S., Electronics and Computer Engineering

February 2011

• Minor: Mechanical Engineering

Chiho Choi, Ph.D.

PUBLICATIONS

Journal Articles

[J1] H. Ma*, Y. Sun*, J. Li, M. Tomizuka, and C. Choi. "Continual Multi-agent Interaction Behavior Prediction with Conditional Generative Memory". *IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L) vol.* 6, no. 4, Oct. 2021.

Refereed Conference Proceedings

- [C19] H. Ma, J. Li, R. Hosseini, M. Tomizuka, and C. Choi. "Multi-objective Diverse Human Motion Prediction with Knowledge Distillation". *In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)* 2022, to appear.
- [C18] R. Ghoddoosian, N. Agarwal, I. Dwivedi, C. Choi, V. Athitsos, and B. Dariush. "Weakly-Supervised Online Action Segmentation in Multi-view Instructional Videos". *In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)* 2022, to appear.
- [C17] J. Li*, H. Gang*, H. Ma, M. Tomizuka, and C. Choi. "Important Object Identification with Semi-Supervised Learning for Autonomous Driving". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)* 2022, to appear. arXiv: 2203.02634
- [C16] H. Girase*, H. Gang*, S. Malla, J. Li, A. Kanehara, K. Mangalam, and C. Choi. "LOKI: Long Term and Key Intentions for Trajectory Prediction". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)* 2021. arXiv: 2108.08236
- [C15] J. Li, F. Yang, H. Ma, S. Malla, M. Tomizuka, and C. Choi. "RAIN: Reinforced Hybrid Attention Inference Network for Motion Forecasting". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)* 2021. arXiv: 2108.01316
- [C14] C. Choi*, J. H. Choi*, J. Li, and S. Malla "Shared Cross-Modal Trajectory Prediction for Autonomous Driving". *In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)* 2021, Oral presentation (4.2% acceptance rate). *arXiv:* 2011.08436
- [C13] S. Malla, C. Choi, and B. Dariush "Social-STAGE: Spatio-Temporal Multi-Modal Future Trajectory Forecast". In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2021. arXiv: 2011.04853
- [C12] J. Li, F. Yang, M. Tomizuka, and C. Choi. "EvolveGraph: Multi-Agent Trajectory Prediction with Dynamic Relational Reasoning". *In Proceedings of the Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)* 2020. arXiv: 2003.13924
- [C11] C. Choi, S. Malla, A. Patil, and J. H. Choi. "DROGON: A Trajectory Prediction Model based on Intention-Conditioned Behavior Reasoning". *In Proceedings of the Conference on Robot Learning* (CoRL) 2020. arXiv:1908.00024
- [C10] I. Dwivedi, S. Malla, B. Dariush, and C. Choi. "SSP: Single Shot Future Trajectory Prediction". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)* 2020. arXiv: 2004.05846
- [C9] S. Malla, B. Dariush, and C. Choi. "TITAN: Future Forecast using Action Priors". *In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)* 2020, Oral presentation (5.7% acceptance rate). arXiv:2003.13886
- [C8] S. Bae, D. Saxena, A. Nakhaei, C. Choi, K. Fujimura, and S. Moura. "Cooperation-Aware Lane Change Maneuver in Dense Traffic based on Model Predictive Control with Recurrent Neural Network". *In Proceedings of the American Control Conference (ACC)* 2020. arXiv:1909.05665
- [C7] C. Choi and B. Dariush. "Looking to Relations for Future Trajectory Forecast". In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2019. arXiv: 1905.08855
- [C6] Y. Yao, M. Xu, C. Choi, D. Crandall, E. Atkins, and B. Dariush. "Egocentric Vision-based Future Vehicle Localization for Intelligent Driving Assistance Systems". *In Proceedings of the IEEE*

Chiho Choi, Ph.D.

- International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2019.
- [C5] M. Liu, F. Yao, C. Choi, A. Sinha, and K. Ramani. "Deep Learning 3D Shapes Using Alt-az Anisotropic 2-Sphere Convolution". *In Proceedings of the International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)* 2019.
- [C4] **C. Choi**, S. Kim, and K. Ramani. "Learning Hand Articulations by Hallucinating Heat Distribution". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)* 2017.
- [C3] C. Choi, S. H. Yoon, C. N. Chen, and K. Ramani. "Robust Hand Pose Estimation during the Interaction with an Unknown Object". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)* 2017.
- [C2] **C. Choi***, A. Sinha*, and K. Ramani (* Co-first Author, order changed for emphasis). "DeepHand: Robust Hand Pose Estimation by Completing a Matrix Imputed with Deep Features". *In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)* 2016.
- [C1] C. Choi, A. Sinha, J. H. Choi, S. Jang, and K. Ramani. "A Collaborative Filtering Approach to Real-Time Hand Pose Estimation". *In Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)* 2015.

Workshop Papers

- [W3] H. Ma*, Y. Sun*, J. Li, M. Tomizuka, and C. Choi. "Continual Multi-agent Interaction Behavior Prediction with Conditional Generative Memory". *In ICCV Workshop on Multi-Agent Interaction and Relational Reasoning 2021*, **Best Paper Runner-up**.
- [W2] J. Li, F. Yang, M. Tomizuka, and C. Choi. "EvolveGraph: Multi-Agent Trajectory Prediction with Dynamic Relational Reasoning". *In NeurIPS Workshop on Machine Learning for Autonomous Driving* 2020.
- [W1] C. Choi and B. Dariush. "Learning to Infer Relations for Future Trajectory Forecast". *In CVPR Workshop on Precognition: Seeing through the Future 2019.*

Non-Refereed Papers / Preprints

- [T5] R. Hosseini, H. Ma, K. Panetta, and C. Choi. "A Framework for Predicting Future Frames using Diverse Sampling". *November* 2021.
- [T4] S. Su, C. Peng, J. Shi, and **C. Choi**. "Potential Field: Interpretable and Unified Representation for Trajectory Prediction". *November* 2019. arXiv:1911.07414
- [T3] S. Malla, I. Dwivedi, B. Dariush, and C. Choi. "NEMO: Future Object Localization Using Noisy Ego Priors". *September 2019. arXiv:1909.08150*
- [T2] **C. Choi**, S. Kim, J. H. Choi, and K. Ramani. "Embedding Compressive Layers in Deep Neural Networks". *Technical Report, Purdue University, May 2017*.
- [T1] C. Choi and S. You. "Dense and Reliable Shape Matching using 3D Particle Filtering". *Technical Report, University of Southern California, May 2013.*

Thesis

[D1] C. Choi. "Computational Learning for Hand Pose Estimation". Ph.D. Dissertation, Purdue University, Jan 2018.

PATENTS

- [P21] H. Ma, J. Li, R. Hosseini, and C. Choi. "Accuracy Prior and Diversity Prior Based Future Prediction". Application pending.
- [P20] R. Hosseini, H. Ma, and C. Choi. "System and Method for Predicting Future Frames using Diverse Sampling". Application pending.
- [P19] R. Ghoddoosian, N. Agarwal, I. Dwivedi, C. Choi, and B. Dariush. "System and Method for

Chiho Choi, Ph.D. 4/6

Providing Weakly-Supervised Online Action Segmentation". Application pending. US 17/590379

- [P18] J. Li, H. Gang, H. Ma, and C. Choi. "Object Identification". Application pending. US 17/411894
- [P17] H. Girase, H. Gang, S. Malla, J. Li, A. Kanehara, and C. Choi. "System and Method for Providing Long Term Key Intentions for Trajectory Prediction". Application pending. US 17/352540
- [P16] H. Ma, J. Li, and C. Choi. "System and Method for Completing Continual Multi-Agent Trajectory Forecasting". Application pending. US 17/380224
- [P15] C. Choi, S. Malla, and S. Bae. "System and Method for Completing Trajectory from Agent-Augmented Environments". Application pending. US 17/161136
- [P14] J. Li and C. Choi. "System and Method for Reinforced Hybrid Attention for Motion Forecasting". Application pending. US 17/173460
- [P13] S. Malla, C. Choi, and B. Dariush. "System and Method for Providing Social-Stage Spatio-Temporal Multi-Modal Future Forecasting". Application pending. US 17/160747, CN 202110727535.9
- [P12] C. Choi. "System and Method for Shared Cross-Modal Trajectory Prediction". US 16/989066
- [P11] J. Li and C. Choi. "Systems and Methods for Heterogeneous Multi-Agent Multi-Modal Trajectory Prediction with Evolving Interaction Graphs". US 17/024080
- [P10] I. Dwivedi, **C. Choi**, S. Malla, and B. Dariush. "Composite Field based Single Shot Prediction". US 16/917864, CN 113379096, JP 2021136019
- [P9] S. Malla, C. Choi, and Behzad Dariush. "System and Method for Future Forecasting using Action Priors". US 16/913260, JP2021070471A
- [P8] S. Su and C. Choi. "System and Method for Providing an Interpretable and Unified Representation for Trajectory Prediction". US 16/911661
- [P7] A. Nakhaei, K. Fujimura, C. Choi, S. Bae, and D. Saxena. "System and Method for Providing Cooperation-Aware Lane Change Control in Dense Traffic". US 16/844331, CN112537306A, JP2021046193A
- [P6] S. Malla and C. Choi. "System and Method for Providing Future Object Localization". US 16/828343
- [P5] C. Choi. "Trajectory Prediction". US 11/087477, WO2021021355A1
- [P4] Y. Yao, M. Xu, C. Choi, and B. Dariush. "System and Method for Egocentric-vision based Future Vehicle Localization". US 16/386964, CN110895674A, JP6833936B2
- [P3] C. Choi. "Methods and Apparatuses for Future Trajectory Forecast". US 11/062141
- [P2] A. Sinha, C. Choi, J. H. Choi, and K. Ramani. "Method of training neural networks for hand pose detection". US 10/503270
- [P1] A. Sinha, C. Choi, J. H. Choi, and K. Ramani. "Method and System for Hand Pose Estimation". US 10/318008

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Students Supervised

- Manh Huynh (Ph.D.), from University of Colorado Denver
- Behrad Toghi (Ph.D.), from University of Central Florida
- Hengbo Ma (Ph.D.), from University of California Berkeley
- Harshayu Girase (M.S.), from University of California Berkeley
- Reza Ghoddoosian (Ph.D.), from University of Texas Arlington
- Ramtin Hosseini (Ph.D.), from Tufts University
- Jiachen Li (Ph.D.), from University of California Berkeley
- Crane He Chen (Ph.D.), from Johns Hopkins University
- Shan Su (Ph.D.), from University of Pennsylvania
- Sangjae Bae (Ph.D.), from University of California Berkeley

January 2022 – Present

September 2021 – Present

January 2021 – Present

January 2021 – Present

May 2021 – December 2021

May 2021 – September 2021

September 2019 – May 2021

January 2021 – April 2021

July 2019 – December 2020

May 2020 – August 2020

Chiho Choi, Ph.D. 5/6

June 2019 – September 2019

• Yu Yao (Ph.D.), from University of Michigan

May 2018 – August 2018

Teaching Assistant

Purdue University

January 2015 – May 2015

ME 444: Computer-aided Design and Rapid Prototyping

Introduction to advanced computer-aided design for product design, modeling, and prototyping.

• University of Southern California

August 2012 – December 2012

CSCI 588 (graduate-level course): Specification and Design of User Interface Software

A design and implementation of user interface software relating to human/computer interaction.

INVITED TALKS

• Kwangwoon University, Seoul, Korea

November 2021

Guest Lecturer: Behavior Prediction for Autonomous Systems

• ICCV Workshop on Benchmarking Trajectory Forecasting Models

October 2021

Presentation: Shared Cross-Modal Trajectory Prediction for Autonomous Driving

• Samsung Advanced Institute of Technology

September 2021

Seminar: Trajectory Prediction in Multi-Agent Interacting Environments

• Purdue University

December 2017

Guest Lecturer: Introduction to Pose Estimation – Probabilistic models in computer vision

ACADEMIC SERVICES

Publication Committee

Honda Research Institute USA

2020, 2021, 2022

Organizing Committee

• Co-organizer: Workshop on *Multi-Agent Interaction and Relational Reasoning* in conjunction with IEEE ICCV 2021

Program Committee / Reviewer

- European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) 2020, 2022
- International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2021, 2022
- IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2018, 2019, 2020, 2021, 2022
- Association for Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2020, 2021, 2022
- International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2021, 2022
- IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV) 2021, 2022
- Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2020, 2021
- IEEE International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) 2021
- IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2019, 2021
- Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV) 2018, 2020
- IEEE Intelligent Vehicles Symposium (IV) 2020
- ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI) 2019
- IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)
- IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Vehicles (T-IV)
- IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (T-IP)
- IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (T-MM)

HONORS and AWARDS

Chiho Choi, Ph.D.

• ICCV Workshop on Multi-Agent Interaction and Relational Reasoning October 2021 Best Paper Award Runner Up

• Ministry of Education, Science and Technology, Korea 2003, 2007, 2009, 2010 *National Science and Technology Scholarship*

MEDIA COVERAGE

- LOKI: An intention dataset to train models for pedestrian and vehicle trajectory prediction, Tech Xplore, September 9, 2021.
- Looking to Relations for Future Trajectory Forecast, ICCV Daily Magazine, October 30, 2019.
- AI Can Predict the Future Location of Vehicles, NVIDIA NEWS Center, September 27, 2018.
- Freeing Our Fingers: Handing Over VR's Toughest Challenge to GPUs, NVIDIA Blog, August 24, 2016.
- AI and VR: New Experiments at Purdue University, ENGINEERING.com, June 30, 2016
- DeepHand motion tracking enters the VR arms race, New Atlas, June 23, 2016
- New tool for virtual and augmented reality uses 'deep learning', Purdue News, June 22, 2016.

REFERENCES

Available upon request